

Paschall Davis

Software Engineer







As an engineer with a proven record of technical skills, strong principles, leadership, and team focus through my seven years working in technology, I'm searching for roles where I can collaborate with highly motivated likeminded developers as we strive to continue learning and deliver excellent software. I thrive in environments with enough structure to provide stability, while still having enough flexibility for occasional explorations into optimizations and new technology.

Contact me

Education

Yale University

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering • 2014

- Two-time varsity swim team letter earner
- Top 8 finisher in the 100 yard freestyle at 2013 Ivy Championship Meet Swim team treasurer and volunteer assistant coach 2013-14 season

Skills

Languages

Java (expert), Python (some experience)

Kubernetes, Helm, Docker, Postgresql, Spring Boot, Git, AWS, ArgoCD, Terraform, Axon

Technologies

Framework, Kafka, SonarQube, Quarkus

Development Practices Continuous Integration and Delivery, Extreme Programming, Test Driven Development,

Pair Programming

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (April 2020)

Certifications

MoneyLion

Experience

Lead Backend Engineer • Jan 2020 — Present

Recognized as leader and top performer by three promotions to Senior, Team Lead, and Lead Engineer levels

- Rewrote Checking Account product using Spring Boot and Axon Framework to integrate with new banking provider and achieve higher levels of scalability and
- customer satisfaction Identified opportunity for optimizations on premium "turbo" transactions and swiftly implemented them to protect customers from a confusing user experience • Led initiative to track code quality and test coverage with SonarQube, resulting in
- from all developers to write tests • Designed a serverless architecture for an integration with Plaid to save money and deliver higher availability while maintaining developer experience

an increase of test coverage from ~25% to >80% across all services and a buy-in

sharing the structure with the greater engineering organization • Developed a set of shared libraries to ensure that the code within the libraries can be tested, packaged, and consumed independently across the Banking team's

Introduced a pattern for blameless retrospective meetings on my team before

Royal Bank of Canada Software Engineer • Mar 2018 — Jan 2020

automating infrastructure and security within RBC

many microservices

• Managed Jenkins CI/CD pipeline to test and deploy to container orchestration platform in an efficient and scalable manner

 Expanded client on-boarding and incident management process to enable platform consumer growth to over 50 internal teams

Built and supported a system of ~25 Spring Boot Java microservices for

provide MariaDB run on Kubernetes to developer teams Led team retrospective and weekly Kanban project grooming meetings

Assisted with implementation and support of Databases as a Service project to

Sr. Tier 2 Technical Support Engineer • May 2015 — Feb 2018

Junior to Senior level

Innovid

• Resolved complex client issues related to ad serving on publisher websites and proprietary application defects

initiative to introduce Knowledge Centered Support practices across the team • Developed custom MySQL reports to fulfill client requests and provide data to the

• Trained and advised junior teammates throughout support ticket process and led

Repeatedly recognized as a leader and top performer with two promotions from

- internal Analytics team • Effectively communicated and collaborated with colleagues and clients with various levels of technical backgrounds to manage critical projects

Running

Outside Interests

• League of Legends esports Fantasy novels

• Music

- Cooking
- Mixology

Made by Paschall Davis with help from jglovier's **Jekyll resume template**.